Contact

760-791-8818 (Mobile) cramirez7@roadrunner.com

www.linkedin.com/in/carlosramirez-rn-bsn-msn-b0450810 (LinkedIn) carlosramirezrn.com (Personal)

Top Skills

Nursing

Hospitals

Home Care

Languages

English (Full Professional)
Spanish (Full Professional)

Honors-Awards

HomeCare Elite 2011, 2012, 2013, 2014, 2015, 2016, 2017, 2018

Hospice CHAP Accreditation 2016

Revenue Budget Achievement Q1, Q2, Q3, Q4 - 2014

Exceeding 2014 Budget Performance

Best Revenue Performance 2014

Publications

University of Phoenix added a new video: Alumnus Carlos Ramirez's Story – University of Phoenix.

Carlos Ramirez-University of Phoenix Ads and Social Media

Phoenix Focus-Alumni Magazine Summer 2015

Willingness to use hospice care among caregivers of Latino patients in the United States-Mexico border region

Carlos Ramirez RN,BSN,MSN

Regional Director of Operations at AccentCare, Inc.

Greater San Diego Area

Summary

Highly skilled career professional with more than 25 years practical experience in leadership, nursing management, health care administration of home health, hospice, hospital critical care, emergency department, intensive care unit, outpatient services, nursing orientation, training, nursing education, and public speaking.

Experience

AccentCare, Inc.

11 years 9 months

Regional Director Of Operations
January 2018 - Present (2 years 7 months)

El Centro, San Diego, & San Marcos; California

As an RDO my duties include:

- •Responsible for recruiting, hire, train, manage and provide ongoing development for Executive Directors and Clinical Supervisors.
- •Provide direction and guidance in the oversight, implementation, and adherence to internal policies and procedures
- •Provide assistance in the review and analysis of financial, clinical, and operational performance indicators and provide feedback to the General Manager and local management teams.
- •Maintain current knowledge of program policy, service and license compliance requirements for agency programs.
- •Participate in the evaluation of agency performance through the annual evaluation process, quality assurance and performance program and periodic review of operations.
- •Partner with the location leadership to assist in the hiring of a competent workforce, as needed.
- •Support and communicate the organization's goals, priorities, and professional standards.
- •Work with location leadership to ensure effective report management and understanding of the data elements and overall impact to the branches.

- •Develop and implement effective clinical and business management systems, oversees the audits of client charts, client satisfaction surveys and all service delivery within the region by conducting routine program audits, as assigned.
- •Guide Executive Directors in all operational areas including process and personnel management.
- •Make site visits to locations and provides professional development and training to achieve optimum staff performance.
- •Ensure location leaders are kept abreast of assigned product lines, programs and services. Participates in the education of these to front-line caregivers, as directed.
- •Comply with applicable legal requirements, standards, policies and procedures including, but not limited to the Compliance Program: Code of Conduct, HIPAA and Documentation Standards.
- •Ensure a high level of customer service to our patients/clients and each other at all times.

Executive Director

November 2008 - January 2018 (9 years 3 months)

El Centro, CA

Responsible for all clinical and business functions of the agency and its branches, including budget, clinical operations, billing and collections, quality improvement, compliance with regulatory and accreditation requirements, human resources, business development and clinical program development. Management of the quality and safe delivery of home health & hospice care services, ensuring to coordinate provision of home health & hospice care services that reflect the home health & hospice care agency philosophy and standards of home health & hospice care.

Planning, development, implementation, and evaluation of home health & hospice agencies services programs and activities.

Responsible for ensuring quality and safe delivery of nursing care services. Provide public relations with the community-at-large, as well as organizations and individuals involved in the health field.

Function as the Privacy Officer Designee (POD) and as a compliance liaison to support and provide leadership within the assigned area of responsibility with accountability for implementing and monitoring the Compliance Program and the relevant requirements including the Code of Conduct, Documentation Compliance and HIPAA.

Committed to the values and mission of AccentCare, Inc.

www.carlosramirezrn.com

Motivational Speaker & Leadership Coach 2014 - Present (6 years)

El Centro, California

Carlos Ramirez is a licensed RN, BSN, MSN, is completing a Doctoral degree in Health Administration (DHA). Currently a Regional Director of Operations and a former Executive Director for AccentCare Home Health & Hospice Inc. El Centro, CA. branch Carlos has received multiple recognitions and is credited for creating transformational change within the organization, during the past 8 years he has increased the client census from 65 to 800, managing a 5 star multi million Medicare certified agency. With Carlos' leadership the agency has received the prestigious Homecare Elite 500 recognition for 7 consecutive years, while managing to maintain the highest employee retention, and satisfaction in the organization.

During his 21 years of professional career as a Registered Nurse, ER Manager, Critical Care and Home Health Director, and Executive Carlos has received multiple awards and recognitions including: Hospital Shining Star Award, Agency Revenue Achievement Award, Fastest Growing Agency Award, 12 consecutive Revenue Budget Achievements, and AccentCare's Leader of the Year 2016 & 2017.

Commercial & Social Media Links:

https://youtu.be/cxBAylzH-sU

https://www.facebook.com/universityofphoenix/videos/10154655827321049/https://www.facebook.com/universityofphoenix/videos/10154667376861049/https://www.facebook.com/universityofphoenix/videos/10154695493241049/https://www.facebook.com/universityofphoenix/videos/10154722549506049/https://www.facebook.com/universityofphoenix/videos/10154854523921049/https://www.udel.edu/udaily/2017/may/staff-appreciation-luncheon/

Carlos is available for the following:

- College/University Events
- Inspirational/Motivational Events
- · Leadership Training
- Professional Excellence and Customer Service in Organizations
- Transforming Health Care Organizations (Hospital, Clinics, Home Health)

To Contact Carlos Ramirez:

Email: cramirez7@roadrunner.com

Telephone: (760)791-8818 www.carlosramirezrn.com

http://www.localhealthauthority.org/about-us/lha-commission/meet-the-commissioners

Commissioner (Non-Physician Member) Local Health Authority (LHA) March 2017 - Present (3 years 5 months)

Imperial County

Independent public entity authorized to improve access to primary care and related specialty and ancillary services.

Promote the long-term viability of safety net providers.

Monitor and publicize performance of the Medi-Cal plans; and increase prevention, education, and early intervention services.

Top-level, decision-making body pushing forward an agenda to improve collective efforts and create sustainable financing for vital health and wellness activities in the community.

Imperial Valley Community College Professor of Nursing -Adjunct Faculty September 2008 - January 2018 (9 years 5 months) Imperial Valley College

Responsible for the clinical learning experiences for nursing procedures, medication administration, and critical thinking for 3rd. semester nursing students.

Educational emphasis in students' training and experience in the Medical Surgical, Geriatric, DOU, ICU and ER departments.

Assist to develop and implement curricula in order to prepare students adequately for the challenges presented within all aspects of the nursing field. Assist to revise nursing program where and when necessary.

In addition to classroom teaching, assist to supervise and advise students, and conduct clinical research when required.

Imperial Valley Home Health
Director of Patient Care Services
November 2007 - April 2009 (1 year 6 months)
Imperial Valley Home Health

The DPCS is responsible for the management of the agency's clinical operations, personnel performance, and delivery of quality clinical services. S/he assures compliance with federal, state, and local regulations as well as accreditation standards and assists the Executive Director (ED) in achieving

budget goals. The DPCS assumes the ED responsibilities in the absence of the ED.

Pioneers Memorial Healthcare District
Charge Nurse - ICU
January 2003 - November 2007 (4 years 11 months)
PMHD Hospital

El Centro Regional Medical Center (ECRMC) Director of Critical Care and Out Patient Services January 1995 - November 2003 (8 years 11 months) El Centro, California

In charge of ER, ICU and Out Patient Services

Education

University of Phoenix-San Diego Campus

Doctor of Health Administration (DHA), Nursing Administration (2012 - 2018)

University of Phoenix-San Diego Campus MSN, Nursing Science (2006 - 2009)

University of Phoenix-San Diego Campus BSN, Nursing Science · (2003 - 2006)

Imperial Valley College
Associate of Science (AS), Registered Nursing/Registered
Nurse · (1991 - 1996)

Holtville High School
Diploma, General Studies · (1988 - 1991)